#### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/jimmysimien (LinkedIn) www.simienproperties.com (Company) www.homesbyjimmy.com (Personal) blogs.har.com/530/Jimmy-Simien's %20Blog (Blog)

Top Skills Real Estate Foreclosures

Sellers

# Jimmy Simien

Broker/Owner

Houston, Texas

## Summary

Who better to turn to for your real estate needs than someone who grew up and raised a family in your area and who's built a lifetime of contacts and knowledge of the Clear Lake area. A Clear Lake High School and University of Houston-Clear Lake graduate, Jimmy started his career in banking and eventually earned his real estate license in 2002. In 2009, Jimmy branched out on his own and Simien Properties was born. Jimmy prides himself in taking care of his clients in every aspect of real estate, long after the sale is complete. His integrity, in-depth community and market expertise, effective negotiating skills and extensive network of contacts in the area allow him to serve any client in any real estate transaction. His success is evident in the numerous word-of-mouth referrals he continuously receives.

- -Broker/Owner of Simien Properties
- -Member of National Association of Realtors
- -Member of Texas Association of Realtors
- -Member of Houston Association of Realtors
- -Clear Lake Resident for more than 30 years

## Experience

Simien Properties

Broker/Owner

January 2009 - Present (11 years 7 months)

Over \$150 million in career sales

Assist agents in generating and converting leads

Manage new agents through complete sales cycle

Develop and maintain client database

List and sell properties: Including commercial, residential, unimproved land and lots

Work in tandem with cooperating agents, lenders, appraisers, inspectors and title companies

Service local buyers and sellers as well as relocation clients

#### **RE/MAX SPACE CENTER**

**Broker Associate** 

May 2002 - August 2008 (6 years 4 months)

Real estate profession specializing in residential and commercial sales

Platinum producing licensed real estate broker with top performing Sales

Team

Managed team of agents with varying sales experience

Annual team sales in excess of \$10,000,000

#### **ENRON CORP**

Senior Finance Specialist

October 1999 - December 2001 (2 years 3 months)

Managed bank relationships between Corporate Global Finance and other

business units

Coordinated finance activities between Enron and outside banks

Served as bank relationship contact on Letters of Credit and loan

documentation

Created blueprint for Bank Deal Database (GOFIR)

Obtained and track bank deal information within database

Prepared weekly syndication, financing and fee reports

#### THE TORONTO-DOMINION BANK

Project Manager

June 1999 - October 1999 (5 months)

#### **Credit Administration**

Manager

February 1997 - June 1999 (2 years 5 months)

#### THE TORONTO-DOMINION BANK

Assistant Manager, Liability Management

November 1994 - February 1997 (2 years 4 months)

#### THE TORONTO DOMINION BANK

Senior Loan Accounting Officer

April 1993 - November 1994 (1 year 8 months)

#### THE TORONTO-DOMINION BANK

Loan Accounting Officer May 1992 - April 1993 (1 year)

Oversaw staffing within new business product areas

Created and implement new department procedures and trained staff including managers.

Managed and analyzed departmental activities

Reviewed, analyzed and executed credit agreements

Facilitate daily client activity such as advances, interest and fee payments

Served as liaison between legal counsel and credit officers

Administered capital market products: swaps, notes, bonds, corporate deposits

Executed swap and capital market documentation

Responsible for settlement of internal funding bank wide: foreign and domestic

Helped support other areas throughout the bank as needed

### Education

University of Houston-Clear Lake Bachelor of Science, Finance · (1992 - 1994)

University of Houston-Clear Lake
Bacherlor of Science, Finance · (1992 - 1994)